<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Karthik Balakrishnan</title>
    <description>Karthik Balakrishnan is a developer by day and activist by night. He has been involved with numerous online movements such as #SaveTheInternet, ChennaiRains.org, #SaveTheMap, etc.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 17:17:15 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 17:17:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>RC.init()</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://recurse.com&quot;&gt;The Recurse Center&lt;/a&gt; is only as good as the effort you put into it. Being entirely self directed is a double edged sword - the flexibility afforded allows for a lot of self exploration, but also makes it very easy to get distracted by all the little things and never really get any work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&quot;making-the-best-of-rc-is-all-about-finding--the-right-balance-between-exploration-and-discipline&quot;&gt;Making the best of RC is all about finding  the right balance between exploration and discipline.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way RC-ers keep themselves on track is to share their plans for the day/week regularly on RC’s internal chat system. The idea being - Sharing your progress regularly will make you more accountable to finish things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m notoriously bad at planning and time management. Discipline is not one of my strong suits. I am easily distracted and can spend days doing lots of small things without getting any meaningful work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is week 4 of 12 at RC and, as suspected, I’ve not got much done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Worked on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/karthikb351/slack-pub&quot;&gt;karthikb351/slack-pub&lt;/a&gt; - a tool to publish your Slack team archives on the internet. It’s great for public Slack communities to share conversations and activity without needing everyone to log in.
Lots more to be done on this, but glad to have at least shipped a simple v0.1.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Worked on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/karthikb351/thumbsdb&quot;&gt;karthikb351/thumbsdb&lt;/a&gt;. A database of episodes of the &lt;a href=&quot;idlethumbs.net/idlethumbs&quot;&gt;Idle Thumbs&lt;/a&gt; podcast - built from their YouTube video descriptions. Rewriting the&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did some reading on &lt;a href=&quot;http://nand2tetris.org&quot;&gt;nand2tetris&lt;/a&gt; - a 12 part course that help you understand computing by starting from the first principles. You start with just a NAND gate and work your way up to making a game of Tetris. With chipsets, assembly code, compilers, and more along the way. I was considering starting this, but I’m not too keen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Played around with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lexaloffle.com/pico-8.php&quot;&gt;PICO-8&lt;/a&gt;. A tiny virtual video game console and IDE for making games (with Lua).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read a bit about making pixel art, and how shading and color palettes work. &lt;a href=&quot;https://brid.gs/slides/pixel-art/#/&quot;&gt;Ayla’s presentation&lt;/a&gt; was the starting point to go down this rabbit role.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explored &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptopals.com/&quot;&gt;The Cryptopals Crypto Challenges&lt;/a&gt;. This seems like an excellent way to gets started with the basics of Cryptography (and is simple enough to learn a new language with)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setup a repository for the censorship detection project &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/InternetFreedomFoundation/watchdog&quot;&gt;InternetFreedomFoundation/watchdog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/recurse-init</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/recurse-init</guid>
        
        
        <category>rc</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
